worldisround.com 2010-06-22

# Privacy Policy on Worldisround

**We guarantee that we will not violate your privacy.**

Overview
     This policy covers how Traveltell LLC, a Delaware Limited Liability Corporation ("Worldisround") collects, manages and protects your personal information. 

'Personal information' is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, e-mail address, and phone number that is not otherwise publicly available. 

This policy does not apply to content that is posted to Worldisround by users or anonymous visitors, including articles, photos and comments. (Such content is not considered 'personal information'.) 

How We Collect Personal Information
     We do not collect personal information about you unless you provide it to us. Most personal information is optional and when personal information is required you can modify it or make it private at any time. 
Information Required for Registration
     To create a new account on Worldisround, you must supply a user name, login name, password, and e-mail address. Your login name and user name can be anything and are always public. Your user name doesn't have to be your real name — you could use your first name, your initials, or any nickname or pseudonym you want. 

Your password is private, of course. The way our technology is set up even we can't tell you what your password is but we can help you change it if you forget it. 

As with most content web sites, passwords are _not_ (currently) encrypted when you log into Worldisround so don't use the same password you use to log into your computer or into a credit card website to log into Worldisround. 

Your 'Country' selection, which is optional, will probably be made public in the future, but it is not at this time. 

Why We Need Your E-mail Address
     You must provide a valid e-mail address when you create a Worldisround account. If your e-mail address is invalid or if we are unable to reach you (which is also possible if you or your e-mail provider marks our e-mails as spam) we may close your account without warning -- because we have no way to contact you! 

Your e-mail address can be hidden or public. If it is public, it will appear on your user homepage and in e-mails sent from Worldisround to friends & family. If the e-mail is hidden, it does not appear on your homepage and e-mails are sent anonymously. 

We encourage users to make their e-mail addresses public on Worldisround. We often get people asking to use photos -- sometimes they are even willing to pay for the rights -- but since the authors have hidden their e-mail address they cannot be contacted. (You retain ownership of your own photos, by the way, and only you can give someone else permission to use them.) And when your e-mail address is public, we do our best to keep third party 'harvesters' from getting it by using a JavaScript trick. 

You may opt in or out of receiving Worldisround announcements (which are currently rare). You may opt in or out of receiving Worldisround notices when one of your articles receives a comment. You can not opt out of receiving account notifications or queries from administrators, which are necessary to maintain your account and deal with special situations. In some cases ignoring Worldisround notifications can result in account cancellation. 

Information Required for Premium Upgrades
     To make a purchase on Worldisround (e.g. upgrading to a Premium account, purchasing more storage, etc.) with a credit card you must supply all of the credit card information that our processor in turn requires, including the card card number, expiration date, billing address, phone number, etc. You choose whether Worldisround may store this information for simplifying future purchases. 

We recognize that this is very sensitive information and we have taken extra precautions to keeping it secure. Whenever credit card information is collected, viewed, or used on Worldisround the information is encrypted with SSL between the web site and your Web browser. 

You Control Your Information
     You can change your user name, e-mail address, password, e-mail options, and privacy settings at any time. 
We Will Not Sell Your Information
     We will not sell or rent any personal information about you to a third party. Aggregate information, such as average age groups or the percentage of hits coming from university accounts, may be revealed to third parties but we will never reveal any other information linked directly to your identity (that is "personally identifiable"). 
Protecting Children's Privacy
     Worldisround complies with the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://www.coppa.org/) (COPPA). The Worldisround web site is not directed at children under 13 years of age but we will allow children to register with Worldisround with their parents' explicit permission and with the understanding that they will use the site only under adult supervision. 

For a child to register with Worldisround, a parent or legal guardian of the child must: 

  * Submit a valid credit card number to verify identity. (This information will not be stored by Worldisround.) 
  * Read and agree to this Privacy Policy and the Worldisround Terms of Use. 
  * Complete the registration form for the child. 
  * Confirm via e-mail that the parent or legal guardian consents to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use. 

If parental consent is provided, personal information that is collected from the child will be treated the same as information collected from any other Worldisround user. Parents and legal guardians may request us to review, modify or delete personally identifiable information about their child at any time. 

We will not knowingly collect personal information of children under 13 years of age without parental consent and if we learn that such information has been inadvertently collected we will promptly delete it. 

Changes to This Policy
     Worldisround may revise, modify or update this policy at any time. We will notify Worldisround users of any significant revisions by sending out an announcement e-mail (if e-mail is being accepted) and/or placing a prominent notice on the web site. 
Cookies
     We use 'cookies' on certain pages of our site. Cookies are bits of data saved by and used specifically for a Web site. Our site only uses cookies that it originated, usually to keep track of a 'user session' that makes logging into the site and writing articles possible. 
Third-Party Advertising
     We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 
Web Site Activity
     We may track information about your Web site activity including what URL you came from (identifying search engines, partner/linking sites, etc.), what browser you are using, and how you navigate the site. This information can help us determine which parts of the site are popular or where navigation may be confusing, and help us improve the site by looking at individual cases. 

We may internally use any information gathered about you to improve our marketing focus, to guide the site features & design, to analyze site usage, and to improve site content. 

We may use your e-mail address to contact you for administrative purposes or to inform you of new site features. 

Exception
     One exception to this policy is that we will release specific information about you or your account to comply with any reasonable, valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute or court order. 
Ask us Questions
     In writing this policy we are trying to be honest, straightforward, complete, and legal all at the same time. If any of these items seems vague or worrisome, please e-mail us at [_info@_ _worldisround.com_](mailto:info@worldisround.com) for clarification.
